We'll be right back.
Let's pray.
All right. Good morning, Canvas. My name is Sherry. I have a few announcements for you. If you are a guest with us, woohoo! If you're a guest with us today, we would invite you to fill out the connection card, and there is a gift in the Welcome Center right outside the door there. We'd love to get to know you a little bit better, and we'd like to give you a gift.
This is an important announcement for parents. As our church community continues to grow, we need to be mindful of the safety of the children. So parents, if you arrive before 9:45 in the morning, please keep your children with you until that time. It's not safe for the kids to be in their classrooms unsupervised, so the doors are going to remain locked until 9:45.
Similarly, please pick up your children directly after church so that we can keep our volunteers free to clean up the classrooms and leave themselves in a timely manner. Once the classrooms are clean, the doors are going to be locked. Also, just be mindful as you leave the building that there's a lot of cars moving around corners and through the parking lot, so please keep an eye on your children because we want them to be safe.
Speaking of kids, our C3 kids are having their second annual Mystery Bus Tour on Saturday, August the 30th from 10 to 8. If you're the parent of a third, fourth, or fifth grader, sign up as soon as possible. This promises to be an event that they will never forget, and last year, apparently, it was pretty awesome.
Speaking of kids, for those who are kids at heart and over 60, we've changed the location of our Legacy Luncheon for today. It is going to be held at Claudio's on Valley Avenue. So, immediately following church, if you'd like to join us, that's where we'll be.
The C3 men's group will host their bacon and bros breakfast here at church this coming Saturday at 8am. I don't know, Sausage and Sisters, anyone? Anyone? I mean, I like bacon, but I'm not a bro, so.
Our new small group called Starting Point meets tonight at 6, and it's going to go from 6 to 8. They will meet in the church lobby. This is targeted for folks that are new to Canvas and are looking to get plugged in.
So, if you'd like to show up, please do, or you can sign up on the website.
Also, online registration is open for the 2025 men's outing.
Join the men on Saturday, September the 19th and 20th at Camp Bethel, and discover what it means to be fathered by God.
The early bird discount ends on August the 31st, so please sign up soon.
Yes, get on it. Let's go, Dave. You tell them. Kevin Sullivan heads up our group of church trustees.
Every Wednesday, they meet here in the evenings to take care of the building.
There's lots of little things that need to be done, and if you're skilled in any kind of area that would be beneficial, please show up.
They work on things like upgrading our flooring, painting, taking care of the exterior, et cetera.
Please reach out to Kevin or Donovan. Is Kevin here? No? Donovan? Everybody knows Donovan?
Reach out to them if this is something that you would be interested in doing. We always need plenty of volunteers.
As far as giving, we have a giving tower at the door there. If you'd like to give to the church, you can also visit our website and go to the online giving button there.
Let's prepare our hearts for a transition to worship. Thanks.
Thank you, Sherry. That's harder than it looks. You guys are pretty intimidating.
The house lights are up a little more than normal, so we can really see your faces. Some of you look grumpy.
Yeah, we have a coffee and brownies and stuff out there, right? That'll make everybody happy.
One more announcement. Exciting times in our youth ministries. We have students bringing friends,
and our congregation in here is growing, too. So we have implemented a student section in the back.
All the black chairs are for our students. If you're not a student, don't jump up right now. It's okay.
But that helps us also kind of get everybody in so the students don't jump up and leave after worship,
and there's a seat here and a seat here and a seat here. So that's really the strategic idea.
And also we want our students to worship together at the opportunity to be among each other.
So that was one more announcement I did not put on Sherry's list.
You guys are asleep today.
I mean, I think Corey and Ballinger are doing great. They're definitely awake.
I hope, I hope that whatever it is, whatever is holding you silent and quiet today,
that you let that go as we worship God as a group, worship God individually, worship God together.
However you want to do that, whatever stance you want to take.
Some of us are excited this morning, some of us are sad, some of us don't know what to feel.
But let's cry out to our God and tell Him how wonderful He is and how thankful we are that He loves us.
Amen? Amen. Okay, good. Let's do it.
I know a name that can silence roaring waves. I know a name that can empty.
Out of grave, I know a name. It's the only name that saves. And it's worthy of all praise. I call you Jesus. I call you, I call you healer. Risen and reigning in power. Something comes out of the grave.
Out of the grave. Every time I call you Jesus. I call you, I call you Savior. Worthy of glory forever. Something comes out of the grave. Every time I call your name. I have a King.
With dominion over death, He holds the King. In His holy male star hands, He is the King. That has brushed the serpent's hand. How resurrected great I am. I call you Jesus.
I call you healer. Risen and reigning in power. Something comes out of the grave. Every time I call you Jesus. I call you, I call you Savior. Worthy of glory forever. Something comes out of the grave.
Every time I call your name, chains break, dry bones awake. Every time I call your name, the gates of hell stay. Every time I call your name, chains break, dry bones awake. Every time I call your name, the gates of hell stay.
Gates of hell stay. Every time I call your name. Every time I call your name. Oh, death is now your name.
Oh, death is now your sting. And when, oh, great your victory. And when, oh, death is now your sting. And when, oh, great your victory.
And when, oh, death is now your sting. And when, oh, great your victory.
Dead things come alive, dead things come alive. Dead things come alive in the name of Jesus.
Dead things come alive, dead things come alive. Dead things come alive in the name that I call you Jesus. I call you, I call you healed. Risen and reigning in power. Something comes out of the grave.
Every time I call you Jesus, I call you, I call you Savior. Worthy of glory forever. Something comes out of the grave. Every time I call your name. Chains break dry bones away. Every time I call your name.
I call your name, the gates of hell shake.
Every time I call your dead things come alive, dead things come alive, dead things come alive in the name of Jesus.
Dead things come alive, dead things come alive, dead things come alive in the name of Jesus.
I call you Jesus. I call you, I call you Healer. Risen and reigning in power. Something comes out of the grave.
Every time I call you Jesus, I call you, I call you Healer. Risen and reigning in power. Something comes out of the grave.
Every time I call you Jesus, I call you, I call you Savior. Worthy of glory forever. Something comes out of the grave. Every time I call your name.
Yes. Give him praise in this place this morning. Amen.
Alright, so our passage today comes from Corinthians. "By the grace God has given me, I laid a foundation as a wise builder, and someone else is building on it. But each one should build with care.
For no one can lay any foundation other than the one already laid, which is Jesus Christ."
Amen.
"If anyone builds on this foundation using gold, silver, costly stones, wood, hay, or straw, their work will be shown for what it is, because the day will bring it to light.
It will be revealed with fire, and the fire will test the quality of each person's work.
If what has been built survives, the builder will receive a reward. If it's burned up, the builder will suffer loss, but yet will be saved, even though only as one escaping through the flames."
I'm worthy of every song we could ever sing. I'm worthy of all the praise we could ever bring. I'm worthy of every breath we could ever breathe. We live for you.
Jesus, the name above every other name. Jesus, the only one who could ever sing. Worthy of every breath we could ever breathe. We live for you. We live for you.
Holy, there is no one like you. There is none beside you. Open up my eyes in wonder and show me who you are. Fill me with your heart and lead me in your love that holds around me.
Jesus, the name above every other. Jesus, the only one who could ever sing. Worthy of every breath we could ever be, we live for you.
Oh, we live for you. Holy, there is no one like you. There is none beside you. Open up my eyes in wonder. Show me who you are and fill me with your heart and lead me.
And lead me in your love to hold the ride.
And I will build my life upon your own.
It is a firm foundation. And I will put my trust in you alone. And I will not be shaken. And I will build my life upon your own.
Upon your love. It is a firm foundation. And I will put my trust in you alone. And I will not be shaken. And holding there is no one like you.
There is none beside me. Open up my eyes in wonder. And show me who you are. And fill me with your heart. And lead me in love to close around. And I will build my life.
Upon your love, it is a firm foundation. And I will build my trust in you alone. And I will not be shaken.
guitar solo
And I'm blown into darkness. Open my eyes, let me see. The beauty that made this heart adore you. The home of a life spent with you.
Here I am to bow down. Here I am to say that you're my God. You're altogether lovely, altogether worthy, altogether wonderful to be.
The King of all grace, oh, so highly exalted. Glorious in all and above. Lovely you came to the earth you created. All for love's sake we came home.
Here I am to worship. Here I am to bow down. Here I am to say that you're my God. You're altogether lovely, altogether worthy, altogether wonderful to me.
And I'll never know how much it costs to see my sin upon that cross. I'll never know how much it costs to see my sin upon that cross.
I'll never know how much it costs to see my sin upon that cross. I'll never know how much it costs to see my sin upon that cross.
Here I am to worship. Here I am to bow down. Here I am to say that you're my God. You're altogether love, altogether worthy, altogether wonderful too.
Here I am to worship. Here I am to bow down. Here I am to say that you're my God. You're altogether lovely, altogether worthy, altogether wonderful too.
You are wonderful, Lord. You are beautiful. He gave you a son of Jesus from the cross for us. Lord, like this song says, we're never going to know what that was like. He died for us while we were still sinners.
Upon that cross, I'll never know how much it costs to see my sin. Upon that cross, so here I am to worship. Here I am to bow down.
Here I am to say that you're my God. You're altogether lovely, altogether worthy, altogether wonderful to me.
We sang today about opening our eyes to see. We ask you boldly, God, open more than our eyes, open our ears, open our hearts, so that you can fill every last little nook and cranny of us with your Spirit.
Let us break down, actually God, let us, you break down those barriers that we have to letting you into all the little spaces in our life that we don't want you to see.
Help us to love you and love each other the way that you so amazingly love us. Please shine your Spirit through Michelle today. She delivers your word. Help us to hear what you want to say through her, God, so that we can let it fill us up and take us out into our daily life so that we can love each other the way you've taught us. In Jesus' name we pray. Amen.
Let's pray.
Good morning, campus community church.
I'm always such the hyper, but it's true it's really hard when you guys are really quiet, so I appreciate it.
If I haven't met you yet, my name is Michelle Meeks. I'm the children's pastor, so typically I'm back there hanging out with the kids.
But this morning, I'm really excited to be here with you as we look at the Book of Psalms.
To be honest, this was tough. Ryan had asked if I would teach one of the chapters of the Book of Psalms, and Psalms is hard because it's like a diary entry, right?
You're mad at God, you're yelling at God for a little bit, and then you're praising God, and it's kind of all over the place, which is really hard to turn into a message.
But as he always does, God has opened my eyes and taught me things that just have blown my mind.
So I'm excited to share with you what he has taught me, but before we do that, I'd love for you to join me in prayer.
Dear Heavenly Father, I thank you for the things that you have taught me. God, I thank you for the Book of Psalms and the honesty and how we can come at you with everything
emotion that we have, and you love us anyway, God. I just pray that your words will be the only words that come to my mouth this morning, and that you will meet everyone in this room right where they are. In your name I pray. Amen.
So this morning we are looking at Psalm 127. I'm going to go ahead and read through the whole thing. It's pretty short, and then we'll kind of break it down, and I can share with you what God has been teaching me.
So Psalms 127 reads, "Unless the Lord builds the house, the builders labor in vain. Unless the Lord watches over the city, the guards stand watch in vain. In vain you rise early and stay up late, toiling for food to eat, for He grants sleep to those He loves.
Children are a heritage from the Lord, offspring a reward from Him. Like arrows in the hands of a warrior are children born in one's youth.
Blessed is the man whose quiver is full of them. They will not be put to shame when they contend with their opponents in court."
So if you looked at this in your Bible, then you would see that this is, Psalm 127 is a Psalm of Ascent of Solomon. So the author of this specific chapter is Solomon.
So I want to take a look at why it's important to know who wrote this specific Psalm. We have Solomon. If you grew up in church, then you know a lot about him.
He was the third king of Israel. His father was King David. But Solomon was actually not supposed to be next in line.
Solomon was the son of David and Bathsheba. You know the story of this. David sees Bathsheba on the roof. He has to have her.
So he arranged for her current husband to be in the front line so that she's killed, he's killed, and then he takes her as his wife.
Not a great thing to do. So the first child that is born to them actually dies.
And Solomon is his second child to this couple. But David had at least six wives before he married Bathsheba.
So Solomon was not the firstborn son, which back then was traditionally the one that would take over the throne when you died.
The one that was supposed to take over was his son, Adonijah. But that's not the plan that God has.
If you look at 1 Chronicles 28:5-7, it says, "Of all of my sons, for the Lord has given me many sons,
he has chosen Solomon, my son, to sit on the throne of the kingdom of the Lord over Israel.
He said to me, 'It is Solomon your son who shall build my house and my courts,
for I have chosen him to be my son, and I will be his father. I will establish his kingdom forever
if he continues strong in keeping my commandments and my rules as he is today.'"
So what an enormous honor. What giant shoes to fill. King David was very popular among his people.
And Solomon, as he knew, wasn't the one that was next in line, but God chose him.
What an honor and a privilege and responsibility. And if you know anything about Solomon,
you know that he started out strong. What is the first thing he does when he is named King?
1 Kings 3:4 says, "Solomon offered a thousand burnt offerings on that altar.
At Gideon, the Lord appeared to Solomon during the night in a dream,
and God said, 'Ask for whatever you want me to give you.'"
"Now, Lord my God, you have made your servant king in place of my father David,
but I am only a little child and I do not know how to carry out my duties.
Your servant is here among the people you have chosen, a great people, too numerous to count or number.
So give your servant a discerning heart to govern your people and to distinguish between right and wrong.
For who is able to govern this great people of yours?"
The Lord was pleased that Solomon asked for this.
So God said to him, "Sent you have asked for this and not a long life or wealth for yourself,
nor have you asked for the death of your enemies, but for a discerning and administering justice.
I will do what you have asked. I will give you a wise and discerning heart,
so that there will never have been anyone like you, nor will there ever be.
Moreover, I will give you what you have not asked for, both wealth and honor,
so that in your lifetime you will have no equal among kings.
And if you walk in obedience to me and give my decrees and commands as your father David did,
I will give you a long life. So Solomon starts off strong. You can see why God chose him.
He is humble. He knows that these gifts that he's been given are not something that he is worthy of.
He knows that he has an entire kingdom that is God's chosen people to reign over,
and he knows he cannot do it in his own strength. So rather than asking for wealth or power,
he just wants to do it the way God wants him to do it. What a great start to being king.
Unfortunately, as many of you know, the humility and fear that he begins his reign with
slowly begin to disappear as his power and money and strength grow. It starts to go to his head.
He starts reigning in his own power rather than the Lord's. And honestly, we see this all the time, right?
You see people that you elect into power who start off humble and begin to change with the power that they get.
Unfortunately, you see it in churches all the time. Many of you come here with church hurt because the pastor that you thought was leaning on God
began, the success of the church began to be his success, not God's success. And he begins to reign in his own strength,
and things fall apart when this happens. And that's exactly what happens with Solomon.
Just to give you an accurate picture of how far Solomon went from being this humble child that leans on God
to being the leader that he becomes, I want to tell you about one of the false gods that Solomon begins to worship
to make one of his many, many, many, many wives happy. This is a drawing of a God of the Amorites called Melech.
So this is just a drawing. There are actual statues of him today. Solomon builds an altar to this guy, to this false God.
And the thing that really gets you about this one is he required infant sacrifice in order to be appeased.
Solomon went from honoring God and saying, "I want to rule with wisdom and discernment to sacrificing infants to this false God."
Scholars say that they would burn his stomach. They would set fire in his stomach, and the whole bronze idol would burn and get hot.
And this is horrible. But you would place the infant on his hands, and it would slide into the burning coals.
I mean, how do you get to this point where you think that this is even remotely okay?
Small decisions, small steps. He went from being a humble man to worshiping this. And this was not just an imaginary false God.
No, 1 Corinthians 10:20 says, "They sacrificed their sons and daughters to the demons. They poured out innocent blood."
He went from worshiping the one true God to worshiping demons. Things changed when he thought he could do it on his own.
So keeping all of this in mind, keeping in mind that this is the author of the one who wrote our text this morning.
Someone who began humble, but ended horribly distant from God, worshiping idols. So go back and look at verses 1 and 2 in Psalms 127.
It reads, "Unless the Lord builds the house, its builders labor in vain. Unless the Lord watches over the city, the watchmen stand guard in vain. In vain you rise up early
and stay up late, toiling for food to eat, for he grants sleep to those he loves."
So this word vain or vanity is seen multiple times in this verse. And so you and I, when we think about vanity,
we think somebody that is full of themselves, right? Spends a lot of time in the mirror, thinks really highly
of their self. That's our definition of vanity. But in Hebrew, the word for vanity was hapel.
Hapel, sorry. And it means something different. It means a vapor, or breath. It means emptiness,
meaninglessness, temporary, like a mist that is here for a moment, and then gone.
So let that sink in. Let's read that again with the definition of vanity.
Unless the Lord builds the house, its builders' labor is like a mist that is here today and gone tomorrow.
It's nothingness. It will not work. So whether this means the thing that you are striving for,
if you are doing it in your own strength, whether this means it won't be accomplished,
or maybe it will and it'll fall apart, or maybe everything will go just as you planned,
but it won't bring you the fulfillment that you thought it would. That's what this means.
And Solomon knew. He knew all the things that he built in his own strength were like a mist.
That we're here today and gone tomorrow because everything he built falls apart when he goes against God.
Look at Ecclesiastes 1:2, which is another one that Solomon wrote.
"Vanity of vanities," says the preacher. "Vanity of vanities. All is vanity."
In other words, emptiness of emptiness. All is empty outside of God.
And like we said, Solomon saw this firsthand. He was one, possibly the richest king that ever reigned.
The Bible tells us he had a yearly income, get this, of 666 talents of gold. Do not think that number is an accident.
This was roughly $1 billion annually just from gold.
If he were around today, we would want him to write a bestseller book so that we could all learn from him, just figure out how we can get 666 talents of gold.
But he does it in his own strength and it falls apart. The queen of Sheba, this is real, the real queen of Sheba, came to visit him to learn from his wisdom.
But it all falls apart. When God was in the center, there was peace.
That was the true gift, not the money, not the buildings, not the power. The true gift was his leaning on God and God giving him peace.
Look at verse 2. "In vain you rise early and stay up late, toiling for food to eat, for he grants sleep to those he loves."
Again, you put the definition of vanity in there. "In emptiness you rise early and stay up late, toiling for food to eat, for he grants sleep to those he loves."
So let's be real, there are times when you have deadlines, and you have to stay up late, and you have to get it done, or you have to get up early, that's not what he's talking about.
He's talking about when you do it in your own strength, and you are striving to get this done morning, night, all day long.
When you're doing it to try to elevate yourself, to make others view you more highly, or maybe there's a part of you that's working on something right now,
that you can't sleep because all of it is on your shoulders. If you think deep down and really think, is it on your shoulders? Are you allowing God to do it?
And to be honest, this is me. Through and through, I do this all the time.
I was on vacation two weeks ago, and all I could think about was being here with you guys this morning and worrying about whether or not I would put the time in and God would speak through me.
And if ever there's something that should be in God's hands, it's this, but yet I still worry.
If you look at that second part where it says, "He grants sleep to those he loves." Who is it that God loves? All of us.
Sleep here is symbolic of your trust in God. Those who realize how loved they are and are able to rest in it because they trust in the sustaining hand of God.
That's how we grant sleep. Last week, Corey talked about how we all want to be microwavable Christians, right?
You just pop us in the oven and 30 seconds later we come out to be like Jesus. Unfortunately, we all know that that's not how it works.
It's the things that you go through in life, the hardships, the struggles, the doubts, the anger, the joy, the happiness, the depression, anxiety.
When you go through those and God gets you through it on the other end, that's what builds your faith in Him, and that's what allows you to sleep.
If you've had a struggle in your life and you can see God's hand in it, then the next struggle that you come to, you remember,
"Okay, He got me through this. I'm going to lean on Him again and I'm going to sleep. I'm not going to try to do it."
And it builds and it builds. That's how we gain wisdom, right? You can't understand that.
When you're a child, I desperately want my children to know the Jesus that I know and your children when I teach them, but they have to go through their walk.
They have to go through their struggles, and Jesus has to show up for them like He so desperately wants to do and will do.
And it's in that that we grow to trust God, and then He gives us peace, peace enough to sleep.
Even in the hard time, my coworker April was talking to me about this week, and she said, "You know, in all the hard things that I've been through,
even the ones that turned out the exact opposite way that I wanted them to, I still see God's hand, and I still see how He was using it."
And so she says, "Now when something hard comes up, I don't pray that it goes the way that I want.
I pray that God's will will be done, and that He will give me the peace that I need to get through whatever it is.
Because even when it's bad, He is still good, and He still has His hand all over this."
Just like Jill said last week, two weeks ago, when she was talking about how David was able to rejoice,
even in the middle of his hardship, how Psalms is written as someone that is freaking out all the way to someone that has peace in God.
It's that journey that gets us to the relationship in God that we need.
Those who are able to rest are not able to because they have accomplished enough,
but because they know that their worth in God is enough.
Tim Keller says in the songs of Jesus, "Sleep is a gift to those who know that they are loved by God and
trust His sovereignty." That is the only way that we will ever find true peace, is realizing how loved we
really are and leaning on that. Solomon repeats this in Ecclesiastes 2:23-23.
"What do people get for all their toil and anxious striving with which they labor under the sun?
In all their days, their work is grief and pain. Even at night,
their minds do not rest." Anybody here? That's definitely me. This, too, is meaningless.
And this was Solomon's life. He had everything, everything that we think will bring us happiness.
But he reaches the end, and he looks back, and he's like, "It was all meaningless. None of it mattered."
What mattered was that moment when I started and I lead on Jesus, and he said, "I'm going to give you wisdom
and discernment." That moment when him and Jesus were lined up together to take on the challenge that struck them,
that was in front of them, that's the best moment of Solomon's life. Not the money, not the power.
It was that moment when he was trusting in God and leaning on Him.
The Bible, what we find out as we live in this life is the world we live in has a definition for success.
That is unattainable. The most empty, miserable people on this planet are those that reach what they thought was going to bring them happiness and contentment.
But when they arrive there, they are emptier than ever because it doesn't. And now they have nowhere else to turn.
That was what Solomon found himself in. He had everything he could ever want, and he realized that it wasn't going to bring his happiness.
And then where do you turn? He turns back to God, and he writes his words of wisdom for all of us to learn from.
So how do we get in this endless cycle that Solomon and so many of us find? The desires for success, but the inability to feel content.
Why do we keep going back to the things that we know won't bring us happiness, but yet we just keep going back to them?
Well, to answer this, I want to go way back, really far back, to Genesis.
We know that in Genesis 3, it describes the fall of man, when sin enters the world, and Eden falls apart.
But what about before that? What was Eden like? I wanted to show you a short clip.
Have you guys seen the movie Encanto? So Antonio, I don't want to show it because it's copyright, and then, you know, it's a whole thing.
But Antonio, the little boy, when he opens the door, and just to be clear, nothing about this movie is Christian,
but this one part, I just love. When he opens his door, his whole room turns into, like, a junk.
It turns into Eden. If you think about it, the animals are his friend. They're talking to him.
I don't know if we'll get to talk to the animals in Eden, but I hope so. I love animals.
But he opens the door, and it's perfect. No one is hurting anyone. He swings from the leg of...
Snakes don't have legs. He swings from a snake. A lion picks them up, and they go running. The animals are all there.
There's plenty. There's fruit. It's Eden. It's the way it was intended to be. There's no fear.
There's nothing to worry about because everything is perfect. Eden was a civilization without greed or malice or envy.
You could have progress without pollution. You could have expansion without extinction.
And we get a little glimpse of this. We get that little glimpse of what Eden might be like.
You know, when winter's over, when you've just went through cold, dark days, and then you have that first day of spring where the sun comes out,
finally, it's 75 degrees, and everybody is outside because you just want to soak in that sun. That's that little glimpse of Eden.
Or that first day when your feet step foot on the sand of vacation, and the waves are crashing, and your kids aren't crying yet.
There's no sand in anybody's eyes. That is a glimpse of Eden, and we know how quickly it falls apart.
But we feel it. Eden is in our DNA. It's stamped on who we are.
C.S. Lewis says, "If I find in myself desires that nothing in this world can satisfy, the only logical explanation is that I was made for another world."
We were made for Eden. That pull, that desire that we just keep missing, it's because God stamped that on our DNA, and we're going back there one day.
This world is going to be redeemed, and we will get to experience Eden with no fear and no pain.
Unfortunately, when sin entered, everything changed. Things that were designed to be a blessing became a curse,
and what was designed to be paradise becomes prison. Because they chose to turn away from God, God banishes them from Eden
and introduces them to pain and mortality. Genesis 3:19 says, "By the sweat of your brow you will eat your food
until you return to the ground, since from it you were taken. For dust you are, and for dust you will return."
If you had the privilege of listening to Sandra Richter when she was here, she talks about this specific verse a lot.
She zones in on the phrase, "By the sweat of your brow." I grew up believing that that meant now work is gonna hurt.
Like, now shovels, there's rocks, and there's thorns, and there's weeds, and all that stuff. And that's true, but it means way more than that.
When sin enters the world, something big happens. The Hebrew word for this is da-aga. If you speak Hebrew, I'm really sorry. Thanks.
It's translated primarily actually as anxiety, worry, fearful concern. It describes an inner unease, a heaviness, or sorrow, not just hard work.
How many of you feel that all the time, that inner unease and that heaviness? That's what happened when sin entered the world needn't fell apart.
We didn't just have to work for things, but now everything has shifted. We have stress, we have self-doubt, we have fear that we might not have enough.
Think about it. Think about what difference it would have been for Adam and Eve before the fall until after the fall.
The world that we are experiencing today is a world that exists because of the fall.
So, before they walked with God, right? And now we have separation with God. No longer do they get to walk with Him and feel His security and His presence.
Imagine walking with God. You have nothing to fear. They didn't even know what fear was because they never experienced pain.
They never experienced hardship. They didn't have to worry about food because it was plentiful.
They never even experienced being hungry. They had peace that we would have never, we cannot even comprehend.
When they had eaten. Then you have the loss of security. Being separated from God meant it led to self-reliance for value and comfort.
How often do we rely on ourselves for that? Everything was scary. The animals that they used to like hang out with and swing with or something now want to eat them.
And they want to eat them because they need them for food. Everything shifts. Now we have fear and insecurity.
We have guilt. What's the first thing Adam and Eve do when God questions them? They hide. They clothe themselves.
They don't go back to the Father and be like, "Oh my goodness, we messed up. We want to be back with you. We're so..." Nope. They hide.
How many of us hide from God when we do something we know we shouldn't have done? And God's like, "I love you. I want you to come to me."
But yet, we hide. And they have uncertainty and vulnerability. Death is now part of the picture. Death was not part of the picture before.
Now they have to worry about pain. They're vulnerable to the things that are around Him.
That's why we are constantly striving after an unreachable goal. Because we live in the fallen world. We don't live in Eden.
Sander teaches us that the world we know is a tragic distortion of what God originally intended.
That's depressing, right? I just told you all these reasons why it makes sense that we feel the way that we do.
But that isn't the end of the story. From the moment sin entered the world, God began to redeem it.
And we are in a very much redeemed world to a certain extent. It's the already but not yet that we live in.
The reality that we see every day is not the full picture, not even close.
God is behind the scenes working in ways that we could never anticipate.
The Bible gives us glimpses of this unseen realm, right?
One of my favorite stories to tell the kids is a story that you will find in 2 Kings 6, when the prophet Elisha is wanted.
There's another kingdom that's coming, and they hate him because he keeps figuring out what they're doing.
And so they figure out where he is, and in the middle of the night, they surround the city.
And so his servant wakes up, and he sees that they are completely surrounded by another army.
And he panics, understandably so. Well, Elijah's cool as a cucumber.
He's like, "What are you panicking about?" And he's like, "We're surrounded. They want you. They're coming after us."
And Elijah prays, and he says, "God, open his eyes so he can see what is really going on."
And in that moment, his servant's eyes are open, and he looks on a hill, and what he sees is a vision of heavenly horses,
and chariots of fire waiting to intervene. See, Elijah saw it. He didn't have anything to fear. God was in control.
His servant only saw what was in front of his face, which is often what we see. But there is so much going on behind the scenes every day.
Another example where the Bible gives us a glimpse of what's going on behind the scenes is revelation. The word revelation literally means a disclosure or an unveiling
of divine truth and knowledge. It gives us a glimpse of what God sees, not worldly knowledge, divine knowledge.
The author of Revelations is John. He was one of the disciples of Jesus, and he's been exiled to the island of Patmos.
Don't let the island of Patmos fool you. This was not a vacation. He was a prisoner. This is where they sent the worst of the worst prisoners.
Scholars believe that the prisoners often worked underground in mines for six days a week.
Prisoners committed suicide. They died from the stress and the pain. It was horrible.
And yet, in the middle of his despair and fear, God chooses to reveal to him a little glimpse of what is going on behind the scenes.
This is one of my favorite pieces of the Bible. Revelation 5:1 says,
"Then I saw in the right hand of him who sat on the throne a scroll with writing on both sides and sealed with seven seals.
And I saw a mighty angel proclaiming in a loud voice, 'Who is worthy to break the seals and open the scrolls?'
But no one in heaven or on earth or under earth could open the scroll or even look inside it.
I wept and wept because no one was found worthy to open the scrolls or even look inside."
So what is this scroll that God is holding in his hand that has seven seals with writing on both sides?
Well, scholars point out that, number one, there was a lot of information on this scroll.
Typically, you didn't write on both sides of paper, but this had writing on both sides.
The other thing is it has seven seals. The only document that had seven seals back then was a will or a testament.
And so this scroll is the deed to the earth. It reveals God's plan of redemption.
But it's sealed and no one is able to open it. If no one can open it, then the plan of God's redemption cannot be fulfilled,
which is why John is crying. In that moment, he feels the way we often do, that there is no hope, and that things will never get better.
And so he weeps. Have you ever felt like that? Like the thing that you're going through right now?
There is no, this is great, that's great that we have a God and stuff like that, but this is too big.
This one that I'm in right now, there's no fixing. That's the way John felt in this moment.
But that's not the end of the story. Not even close. Look at verse five.
"Then one of the elders said to him, 'Do not weep. See, the lion of the tribe of Judah, the root of David, has triumphed.'
He is able to open the scroll in the seven seas." The lion of Judah, the root of David, these are Messianic terms.
The lion has come. The lion has overcome. And then comes that moment where John sees it.
He sees the mighty, powerful lion with muscles bulging out of everywhere, coming in with force and power and might, right?
That's what he sees, right? No. Verse 6 says, "And then I saw a lamb, looking as if it had been slain, standing at the center of the throne."
The Greek word for lamb here is actually irion. Again, I'm sorry for Greek people. It means little lamb.
Then I saw a little lamb, looking as if he had been slain. That's our king. That's the one who took our sin to the cross.
He is able to break the seal. How? Not from being strong and mighty, although he is completely strong and mighty.
Not from being a valiant warrior, but from sacrificial love. He laid down his life for you and I.
How do we overcome the things of this world? How do we gain what Solomon thought he could gain through riches and wealth?
We gain it from sacrificial love. This world is going to tell us the polar opposite of that, right?
You stand up for yourself. You go after what you deserve. You fight back.
Jesus came as a lamb that was slain and sacrificially laid down his life for you and I.
And he's trying to tell you and I, if you want success, you have to give sacrificial love.
It's the only way. Even if it seems wrong, have you ever sacrificially given love to someone and regretted it? I doubt it.
It's the way of the cross. It's what he is begging us to do.
The Bible says that the lamb had seven horns and seven eyes. That's weird, right? Like that changes your, like this little lamb with seven horns, and I was like, that's weird.
But there's meaning. The horns represent strength, and the word seven means complete. He had complete strength.
The eyes represents wisdom and insight. He had complete wisdom. He could have overthrown.
He could have, but he doesn't choose to. He chooses to come as a little lamb who laid down his life for us.
The lamb is reigning right now on the throne. He already conquered death.
The veil has been torn from the top to the bottom, and our hearts are his dwelling place.
One day the earth will be renewed back to the way that Eden was meant, but don't forget he's on the throne now, today.
Even if we can't see the throne in heaven, we need to remember that it's there, and he is king.
He will reign with complete strength and with complete wisdom, yet sacrificial love that he has presented to us, and he's asking us to give out.
We are supposed to be different than the world, right?
That's how you're different than the world, with sacrificial love as Jesus gave us.
So what do we do with this? We set the present moment, the thing that you are struggling with right now, set it in the light of what is unseen, the realities of the present.
You are not alone. We will one day be in Eden, and the sacrificial lamb will be there to welcome us.
So set what it is that you're struggling with, and with that in the back of your mind, always.
How do we get to this constant cycle? Because we focus on what is seen in front of us.
That's not reality. Satan desperately wants us to think it's reality,
so that we can feel just as John felt in that moment where he wept and said, "There is no chance that we will get out of this."
But the reality is that the lamb is seated on the throne, and he loves you more than you could ever imagine.
So much so that he laid down his life, so that separation with God that happened in Eden was taken away,
and we are no longer separated from God. Let's look at this final verses of Psalms 127.
"Sons are a heritage from God, children a reward from him.
Like arrows in the hands of a warrior are sons born in one's youth.
Blessed is the man whose quiver is full of them.
They will not be put to shame when they contend with their enemies at the gate."
I have three children, and never once have I thought of them as being a blessing, because they're warriors for me, to protect our family.
That's not, a six-year-old is not, we're in trouble.
But back then, they would have gotten this, right?
Like your family unit was what protected you, so your children being warriors, they got that.
But I want you to look at the fact that they call the child an arrow.
There were several weapons back then that you could use for war, right?
There were daggers and swords. Those were weapons that have close man-to-man contact, right?
Like you're not gonna stab somebody from a while away unless, I guess, you have really good aim.
And then there are spears and javelin. That you can stand a little bit further back, but still, you have to be close to be able to use these weapons.
And then you have an arrow. An arrow is a weapon that you can send out to accomplish something.
An arrow is a tool that you can send out to make an impact somewhere that you can't be.
Scripture doesn't call a child a sword that would have to be attached to you, but something that you can point in the right direction and send out to fight battles that you yourself are not, should not be close enough to.
I want to tell you a story. So my son had a really close friend, and he talked a lot of, my son would talk a lot about church, and he invited his friend to come to church.
Their family was going through a lot at that time. There was a lot of things going on. Church was not a place they were really comfortable in. They didn't grow up going to church.
But their son would ride with us. Well, unbeknownst to me, after about six months of going to church, my son's friend had some questions.
So on the back porch, I have no idea this is going on, they start talking about God. My son prays with his friend to ask Jesus into his heart. I had no idea.
And then, three months later, his friend tells me that he wants to get baptized. And I was like, "That's amazing."
And I was talking to my son, and I said, "Do you think..." His name is Riker. "Do you think Riker has asked Christ into his life?"
And he's like, "Oh yeah, we did that on the back porch a while ago." I'm like, "What?" And he's like, "Oh, he asked me, and I just told him."
And I mean, I'm the children's pastor. If anybody should have been an adult that was in that conversation, it's me.
But his friend did not want to talk to me. He wanted to talk to his friend. He was the arrow that was in a spot that I cannot be, even if I'm the children's pastor.
They want to talk to their friend. Fast forward, he gets baptized. His entire family comes to church for the first time to watch him get baptized.
Fast forward again, a few weeks ago, I was able to baptize his mom, one of my closest friends. That's because, yeah, it was amazing.
It was amazing. And she's going through so much, and she's leaning on Jesus because her son brought her to church.
That's an arrow that goes out into places that even if you think you can be there, you really can't.
We were blessed with the children of this church because God wants us to send them out, and they are going out.
They're going out. The question is, is what is that arrow pointing at when we send them out?
Charles Spurgeon says, "Sticks are by nature, not arrows."
Children are by nature rugged.
Your child is going to look at the world the way the world tells them to look at it.
That success is gained through others' opinions, money, and power.
Are you shaping your child into an arrow that is aiming at the world's definition of success and happiness?
Because if so, you are sending them out broken and scared with an unreachable target.
If Solomon couldn't reach it with all the power and the wealth, and he says it was all meaningless, it's meaningless.
But we tend to shape our children into reaching those goals anyway, right?
Think about it. What are the goals you have for yourself or your children?
What makes you proud?
What things do you emphasize?
What things do you make a priority?
Is it worldly success or is it godly success?
Have you reminded them of God's truth that peace can only come from God?
That value only comes from God?
That security is what comes from God?
Think about it practically.
Think about what you make a priority and what they know they do that makes you proud.
Does it line up with the world's definition of success or God's?
Look again at what our children are facing. We're facing the same things, right?
They live in the fallen Eden that you and I do. They have that fear of the separation from God.
They struggle with loss and security, fear and guilt, uncertainty and vulnerability.
What they struggle with is very real and should never be downplayed.
They struggle with a world that is throwing a million things at them a minute.
Our children are going to aim to overcome their struggle through worldly standards,
unless we help them see that that's not the end of the story.
When they struggle with each of these things, what guidance are you giving them?
When they struggle with feeling separated from God. Look at Deuteronomy 31:6.
Be strong and courageous. Do not be afraid or terrified because of them.
For the Lord your God goes with you wherever you go. He will never leave you or forsake you.
When they struggle with that loss of security, when fear and insecurity is the struggle that they are dealing with,
remind them that God is with them always.
Philippians 4:6-7 says, "Do not be anxious about anything, but in every situation, by prayer and petition with thanksgiving,
present your request to God, and the peace of God, which transcends all understanding,
will guard your hearts and minds in Christ Jesus." Are you teaching them to pray when they're overwhelmed?
Are you trying to fix their problems? I'm a problem fixer. Yet God is saying, "I am the answer to the problems."
Sacrificial love, remember? I'm seated on the throne now, and I love your child more than you do,
which is mind-blowing for a parent to wrap their heads around. But he does. He laid his life down for them.
When they struggle with uncertainty and vulnerability, remind them of Revelations 5:6.
"Then I saw a lamb, looking as if it had been slayed, standing at the center of the throne."
What they see is not the end of the story. It's not real reality.
The lamb is seated on the throne right now and loves them with sacrificial love.
Rather than striving for worldly success, teach them that success is faithfulness to God.
Not getting on the team, not having the best clothes, not having the most friends.
Success is faithfulness to God and leaning on God.
Success is obedience to God's Word, not obedience to what your friends think that you should be doing,
but leaning on God's Word and obeying it. It's only for our good. It's never been to make things not fun.
It's because God knows what we're up against, and He can see what we can't see.
Are you teaching your child to lean on God's Word? That success is rooted in relationship with Jesus.
Are you teaching them to have a strong relationship with God that they lean on?
That success is measured by eternity. This world is temporary.
The Lamb is seated on the throne, and one day we will be in Eden. We will get to hang out with lions.
I'm swimming with dolphins because I won't have to hold my breath. I can't wait. It's going to be amazing.
Are we reminding them that you're not going to find happiness trying to chase after worldly success,
but you're going to find it if you root yourself in your relationship with God.
And success is becoming like Christ. You can't get there like a microwavable Christian.
It takes time. It takes you going through the hard stuff and God showing up and you realizing,
"You were there the whole time. You never left me." And you have a plan.
If you're sitting here and you're thinking, "I don't have any kids, so this part really isn't for me."
We have on the back tables, which I'll explain more about, 250 bookmarks with the name of a child from elementary to college that go to this church that desperately need your guidance.
I'm going to tell you a story as I close. In 1934, there was a revival happening in Charlotte, North Carolina, led by evangelist Mordecai Hamm.
During this revival, two 14-year-old boys walked up and thought about checking it out. However, when they got to the tent, they realized that it was super crowded and they didn't have any seats, so they gave up and decided to walk out.
However, as they were walking away, an usher noticed them. This usher ran after them, greeted them with a warm smile, made them feel seen and loved, and helped them find two available seats near the front of the revival tent.
Because of this usher's kindness, both boys stayed and listened to the entire message that day, and both boys had decided to give their lives to Jesus.
You may have heard of at least one of these two teenage boys. His name is Billy Graham.
Billy Graham went on to preach to more people than anyone in the world has ever preached. He preached to tens of millions of people who were able to hear the gospel and give their lives to God.
The other boy, the other 14-year-old boy that was with him, his name was Grady Wilson. He was the man that helped Billy Graham plan and organize all of his crusades.
Together, they shared the gospel with tens of thousands of people, and they accepted Christ. This man changed the world.
I'm not talking about Billy Graham or Grady Wilson or even Mordecai Hamm, although all of them did. I'm talking about the usher.
Father, who saw two teenage boys walking away from the tent, and rather than ignoring them, tracked them down, made them feel seen and welcomed before providing them with a seat to hear the gospel for the first time.
Church, that's our role. Our children desperately need them. You, you have no idea how much they need you. They need this church to be a place that they walk in and feel more
welcomed than any other place on earth. They need to feel loved. They need to, even when they're being loud and obnoxious, they need us to be loving
and welcoming because that's how Jesus treats us. And that's how they need to feel when they walk in here. I want this church to be the most welcoming,
loving place that our youth have ever stepped foot in. And that can only be accomplished through you and I. How do we treat our children when they walk in
this building? How do we treat other children? I am begging you to think of these children the way that Jesus thinks as us,
with sacrificial love. Putting yourself aside and giving them what they need because when they go out into the world, they're arrows
that are reaching places that we cannot go. Where are we pointing them? It will just take a few bad situations
of the church that they leave and never come back. We want them to be arrows that point to the only true
peace. God wants to use us to do that. I'm going to pray, and then I would love it if on your way out,
you would choose one of those bookmarks. The bookmarks have a name of a child from kindergarten to college.
It will have their name in either their age or their grade. On this side is the elementary students. On
this side, it's in the back, is middle school through college. What I would like you to do is to put that
bookmark somewhere where you will see it all the time. Put it in your Bible. Put it on your refrigerator.
Choose one child and pray for them this year. Pray that they see Christ like never before. Pray that they can
give sacrificial love rather than to have that desire to be stronger than others or strive after worldly
things. Pray that they see Christ. And as we pray for them, look for them. Maybe find out who they are and
welcome them and just let them know you're praying for them. Allow them to know how loved they are. Let's pray
together. Heavenly Father, we thank you so much for laying down your life for us in sacrificial love.
We will never be able to thank you enough. As the song says, we have no idea what that took, and yet you did
it for us with complete strength and with complete wisdom. God, allow us to strive after you rather than
the worldly things that we know won't ever give us true peace and happiness. Allow us to shape our
children, the children of this church, into arrows that go after your success, not worldly success.
Give us peace, even in the hard times. We know that we are living on the other side of Eden, God, and
that things are really, really hard. But you are there, seated on the throne, and you never leave us or forsake us.
Thank you for this church and for these people. In your name I pray.
Go in peace, church. Please, if you can, pick up a bookmark on your way out.
Thank you.